<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Glass Frog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Glass Frog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Econometrics by Gujarati and Porter</title>
      <link>/books/2020-03-03-basic-econometrics-by-gujarati-and-porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/2020-03-03-basic-econometrics-by-gujarati-and-porter/</guid>
      <description>OverviewThis book is the tipical book reference for a given subject, and when the theme is Econometrics, this material is highly recommended for economics grad students. For its importance, in this post I’ll present a brief summary of each chapter and solve some exercises (because the book doesn’t present the answer for the problems). Also, I’ll release the datasets used on the problems on my github account.
The authors aimed to build a material that would serve all levels of students that want learn econometrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Francisco, an Economist that enjoy working with data and statistics. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s why i&amp;rsquo;m working with Business Intelligence and Data Warehouse since 2015. This field allows me to code (mainly in SQL, R and Python), analyse data using statistics and communicate business research throughout reports and data viz. I try keep learning different tools and models to solve business problems and increase my capacity to generate insights from data in a productive way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting R on Amazon Redshift Database</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/10/connecting-r-on-amazon-redshift-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/10/connecting-r-on-amazon-redshift-database/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionIn this tutorial I’ll show a step by step on how to access Amazon Redshift Database throughout R. This task will be very useful if you prefer to use R intead of the traditional Excel to execute exploratory data analysis on your company. The goal of this tutorial is to access the database from R, bring a data.frame as a result set and then create your analysis.
Step 1Dowload the JDBC driver from Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residual analysis in econometric models</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/09/residual-analysis-in-econometric-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/09/residual-analysis-in-econometric-models/</guid>
      <description>The linear regression model is highly used on the prediction of continuous variables, where is one or more independent variables and one dependent one (the one that it seeks to test an hypothesis about its behavior). This is a pretty simple model to by executed and one of the firsts to be taught in econometric classes. Although its simplicity, in order to reach reliable results, some assumptions are needed, like the following:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>